### **Josh Dixon**

+44 7753334432 | Vancouver, BC

<u>LinkedIn</u> | joshdixon1995@hotmail.co.uk

#### **OBJECTIVE STATEMENT**

A front end software developer with 1.5 years of experience working in an agile environment developing, testing and peer reviewing code that reaches hundreds of thousands of users. Experienced in JavaScript, React, NextJs and PHP. Authorized to work for any Canadian company for two years without LMIA.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# **The Collecting Group Ltd**

Nottingham, UK

Website Developer

September 2021 - Present

Designed, developed and maintained features for two online auction websites (collectingcars.com and watchcollecting.com).

- Tripled the selection of languages available and added translation support due to rapid growth internationally. Also revamped the UX and UI of the language selection React component.
- Optimized development and deployment of static pages by implementing Contentful CMS. This resulted in faster turnaround times for policy page changes, addition of news articles and the ability to deploy static pages independently without requiring developer input.
- Developed microservice for handling user data and displaying badges alongside usernames. Improving trust between reputable buyers and sellers on our platform.
- Conducted an SEO audit and improved page load time and Cumulative Layout Shift (CLS) score, resulting in better search engine visibility and user experience.
- Designed and developed a 'press cuttings' page in response to a business request. The feature allows the web-ops team to input article links in our CMS, which are then rendered as article cards on the webpage using metadata from the provided link.
- Collaborated with stakeholders to build and test a new responsive navigation system for both brands.

#### **Nottingham Forest FC Ltd**

Nottingham, UK

## Team Photographer

September 2021 - Present

- Shoot, edit and caption imagery of matchday events, game action and press conferences.
- Oversaw the organization and maintenance of the club's image archive.
- Provide imagery for corporate partners and sponsors, including imagery of advertising materials, shirt sponsors and stadium branding.
- Produce all content in line with the club's digital strategy and style.

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Frontend: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, React, NextJs, Jest, Cypress, JQuery, XSLT, ChakraUI, Framer Motion Tools: Git, GitHub, CircleCl, PHPStorm, Visual Studio Code, Figma, Contentful, Postman, Hotjar

### **CERTIFICATIONS**

**AWS Cloud Practitioner Essentials** | Amazon Web Services Training **UX and Accessible Design** | UAL Creative Computing Institute

### **EDUCATION**

**Worksop College** Worksop, UK 2011 - 2013

A Levels in Applied Business, Design & Technology and Physical Education

**The Grove Secondary School** 

Balderton, UK

6 GCSE's grade A-C including Mathematics and English

2006 - 2011